

Abel Mitiku

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Email: abelmgetnet@gmail.com Phone No: +251919395958

About Me

I am a Junior Machine Learning/AI Engineer with a software engineering and web development background. Experience utilizing tools like Pandas, Numpy, PyTorch, TensorFlow, Scikit-learn, Seaborn, and Matplotlib. I have experience in data visualization, ReactJS, C#, Java, and building end-to-end machine learning pipelines for artificial intelligence, business, and other areas.

Skills & Proficiencies

- Python, Java, Dart, C#, PHP
- AWS
- MySQL, PostgreSQL
- · DBT, Airflow
- · Git, DVC, MLflow, Docker
- · Numpy, Pandas
- · PyTorch, TensorFlow
- CML, Travis CI
- Tableau
- · Bash, Zsh, shell
- Flutter, Kotlin
- . HTML, CSS, ReactJS

Educational Background

Addis Ababa University

BSc in Electrical & Computer Engineering 2016 - 2022

Relevant Courses

- OOP, Computer Architecture
- MATLAB
- · C++, JAVA
- · VHDL, Verilog
- Applied Mathematics I III
- · Probability and statistics
- · EMFs, Modern Physics
- · Economics

10 Academy

Data Engineering and Machine Learning Engineering

Apr 2022 - Jul 2022

Relevant Courses

A Project-based Intensive training where I got to work on 12 projects that helped me develop the following skill-sets:

- Machine Learning (AI) Pipeline Development
- Data Engineering Principles and Large Scale Implementations
- Web3.0 Dapp Development
- · Statistical Reasoning
- A/B Testing/Business Analysis
- Causal Inference
- Speech recognition
- Data warehouse, Kafka, Airflow



https://github.com/abel-blue



https://www.linkedin.com/in/abel-mitiku-2b95bb215/



https://medium.com/@Abel-Blue



https://sites.google.com/view/abel-mitikugetnet

Projects

Telecom User Data Analytics

This project was to analyze customer behavior in terms of their engagement, experience, and satisfaction for a telecom company and suggest if the company is worthy of buying or selling.

Algorand Blockchain using ReactJS

NFTs are created using Algorand Standard Assets (ASAs), which are built into the protocol and created using a special type of transaction. This is distinct from some other blockchains where a smart contract is necessary to represent assets.

Ethereum Blockchain (Crypto) Smart Contract

Made a mobile App that facilitates when an employer pays an employee, for being present in a certain geographic area for a certain duration. The employee's phone sends its GPS location to a smart contract at a certain interval. Based on the pre-agreed contract codified in an Ethereum smart contract, a cryptocurrency payment is executed when all the agreed conditions are met.

Work Experience

Member, Intern

AI Guild

Data Science, Germany, Remote Dec 2022 - Jan 2023

- Member
- Al Practitioner

Full Stack Developer

Leximd

Romania, Remote

Dec 2021 - Apr 2022

- Ability to program in a programming language such as Java (J2EE), and Python.
- Proficient in React, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS.
- · Proficient in MySQL, and PostgreSQL.

Certification

Data Engineering/ML/Web3.0

10 Academy

Jul 10, 2022

JavaScript, Bootstrap

Udemv

Feb 10, 2022

Youth International Conclave - YIC

Webinar participator

Oct 29, 2021